### Avaljot Singh

Department of Computer Science University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign singhasavaljot@gmail.com avaljot2@illinois.edu

## RESEARCH INTEREST

My current research is focused on making Neural Networks trustworthy by making it easy to verify properties like robustness using formal methods. We are currently building ConstraintFlow, a DSL for defining Neural Network analysis algorithms.

# EDUCATION

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign [PhD]

2022 - Present

Advisors: Prof. Gagandeep Singh, Prof. Charith Mendis

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi [B.Tech + M.Tech]

2016 - 2021

Advisor: Prof. Sanjiva Prasad

### **Publications**

Interpreting Robustness Proofs of Deep Neural Networks

ICLR, 2023

Debangshu Banerjee, Avaljot Singh, Gagandeep Singh

In submission

ConstraintFlow: A Declarative DSL for Certified Artificial Intelligence

SRC @ PLDI, 2023

Avaljot Singh

 $Bronze \ medal$ 

Interpreting Robustness Proofs of Deep Neural Networks

Debangshu Banerjee, Avaljot Singh, Gagandeep Singh

WFVML @ ICML, 2023
Outstanding paper

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

• M4L: Mixed-mode MPC for Machine Learning Rahul Sharma

March, 2021 - June, 2021

MSR Bangalore

- Designed DSL and a type system for **Mixed-mode MPC**
- Proved the **formal guarantees** of correctness and cryptographic security for well-typed programs.
- Algebraic techniques for network routing [M.Tech Thesis]

January 2020 - December 2020

IIT Delhi

Prof. Sanjiva Prasad

oj. Sanjiva Frasaa

- Conservatively extended NetKAT to Cost-InterNetKAT involving three distinct innovations
- Introduced inter-layer routing and cost algebra, thus allowing composition of cost-dependent NetKAT policies
- Designed Cost-InterNetKAT homomorphisms, refinements, absrtractions and translations
- Synthesis and Unified Management of Hybrid Networks *Prof. Nate Foster*

May, 2019 - July, 2019

Cornell University

- Defined the syntax and semantics of Edge-NetKAT
- Pushing the functionality of NetKAT programs to configurable edge devices.
- Object Detection for Local Spotting using 2DOF Actuator

June, 2018 - July, 2018

Prof. Idaku Ishii

Robotics Lab, Hiroshima University

- Implemented a facial recognition system mounted on **mechanical tracking system** for security cameras
- Used **High speed Camera Interfacing** for real-time image synthesis and real-time tracking system

### ContsraintFlow: A Declarative DSL for Certified Artificial Intelligence

- Designing a DSL for DNN Verification and developing its type system and operational semantics
- Automatic verification for over-approximation-based soundness of the DNN certifier specified in ConstraintFlow

### Data Driven Approach for Loop termination

- Designing ranking functions using trace data to prove the termination of loops
- Mutually Reinforcing Development of ranking functions and invariants using program synthesis

### Polynomial abstract domain for Neural Network Verification

- Designing a novel abstract domain and abstract transformers using polynomials
- Enriching the domain of robustness properties for DNN verification tasks

# TEACHING ASSISTANT

Analysis and Design of Algorithms	Spring 2021
Prof. Naveen Garg	IIT Delhi
Introduction to Functional Programming	Fall 2020
Prof. Sanjiva Prasad	IIT Delhi
Programming Languages	Spring 2020
Prof. Sanjiva Prasad	IIT Delhi
Introduction to Computer Science	Fall 2019
Prof. Prem Kalra	IIT Delhi